<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Python and R</title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/11/python-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/11/python-and-r/</guid>
      <description>Let&#39;s talk about Pyhton and Rstudio In the Fall of 2020, I took a course called &amp;quot;Computational Biology and Bioinformatics&amp;quot; at the University of Texas, in which I learned how to navigate Rstudio and Python programming languages. What I found super interesting about these resources is that they aren&#39;t mutually exclusive and that you can actually use them both together! The two coding projects that are located in the &amp;quot;Projects&#39;&#39; tab of this website were completed solely using Rstudio; however, in this post I will show you how one can pull a file from Rstudio and complete Python functions using it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UT Resource Recovery Experience</title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/10/test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/10/test-post/</guid>
      <description>UT Resource Recovery   Reflecting on Past Professional Experience During my junior year of college, which was from Fall 2019 to Spring 2020, I would for the Resource Recovery program at the University of Texas (UT). I was an intern for both their zero waste events and waste audit teams. After a semester of working there, my title was promoted to &amp;quot;Zero Waste Events Specialist&amp;quot;. As someone who desires to spend their life working in the fields of conservation and sustainability, I cannot stress enough how grateful I am for the growth that this internship provided me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FINALPROECT2</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Bird_Nest &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;BirdNest.csv&amp;quot;) Bird_Nest &amp;lt;- Bird_Nest %&amp;gt;% select(- X1, - Page, - Species, - Nestling, - Incubate) Bird_Nest &amp;lt;- Bird_Nest %&amp;gt;% na.omit() Bird_Nest &amp;lt;- Bird_Nest[-c(11, 12, 29, 30, 21, 28),] #these rows had errors with the data (didn&amp;#39;t match the format) Bird_Nest &amp;lt;- Bird_Nest%&amp;gt;%mutate(Color_cat = case_when(Color==1 ~ &amp;quot;Yes&amp;quot;, Color==0 ~ &amp;quot;No&amp;quot;)) #The above code were lines I ran to set up my dataset Throughout this semester, I have been enrolled in a course called &amp;quot;Animal Behavior,&amp;quot; and we have spent a lot of time discussing various species of birds as well as their behaviors (primarily those related to parental care).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analysis (Project 1)</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Considering that we are in the midst of a very important presidential election, I knew that I wanted to revolve this project around politics. With that being said, one of the datasets that I chose to use is titled Election08 and contains information about the 2008 United States (U.S.) presidential election on a state-by-state basis, including the District of Columbia (51 observations total). There are 7 variables within the dataset (all listed/described below) and the data primarily comes from the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Farming Project</title>
      <link>/project/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project3/</guid>
      <description>My sophomore year of college, I was enrolled in a course called &amp;quot;Communicating Sustainability,&amp;quot; which required me to complete the group project located below. For this project, a couple of classmates and I created a fake marketing agency called &amp;quot;GRAMS&amp;quot;. Our goal was to explore the benefits of community farming, in the hopes that we could better market Microfarm, which is a community farm run by students at the University of Texas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FINALPROECT2</title>
      <link>/project/finalproject2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/finalproject2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Bird_Nest &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;BirdNest.csv&amp;quot;) Bird_Nest &amp;lt;- Bird_Nest %&amp;gt;% select(- X1, - Page, - Species, - Nestling, - Incubate) Bird_Nest &amp;lt;- Bird_Nest %&amp;gt;% na.omit() Bird_Nest &amp;lt;- Bird_Nest[-c(11, 12, 29, 30, 21, 28),] #these rows had errors with the data (didn&amp;#39;t match the format) Bird_Nest &amp;lt;- Bird_Nest%&amp;gt;%mutate(Color_cat = case_when(Color==1 ~ &amp;quot;Yes&amp;quot;, Color==0 ~ &amp;quot;No&amp;quot;)) #The above code were lines I ran to set up my dataset Throughout this semester, I have been enrolled in a course called &amp;quot;Animal Behavior,&amp;quot; and we have spent a lot of time discussing various species of birds as well as their behaviors (primarily those related to parental care).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
Here are some of my non-coding related projects:
 Community Farming Project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
